-Morning, Shuji. -Morning!
-修二，早安 -早安
-Let's go in together. -Yes!
-一起進去吧 -好啊
Yes!
帥啦
-What's today's bento? -Today's is…
-今天的便當是什麼？ -今天的便當是…
Every darn one of them is watching us.
大家都盯著我們看
It only makes sense.
這也是理所當然的事
In anyone's eyes, we're the ideal couple.
在別人眼裡，我們是天作之合啊
But I have no intention of dating her properly.
但我完全不想和她正式交往
Doing that kind of thing during this short time in high school is
在短暫的高中生涯做這種事
just way too stupid.
未免也太愚蠢了
It's almost November 4.
11月4日快到了
What? Oh, you mean 114.
什麼？妳是說114日啊
THREE DAYS UNTIL 114. ZERO SIGN-UPS.
（倒數三天，零人報名）
114 DAY
（114日）
-Shuji! -Whoa!
修二
-Okay. Let's do this! -Okay!
-來吧 -好
-There!
-來囉
The lord has arrived!
大王駕到
-Our lord!
-大王
Milord, Takashi James Yamada knows not what 114 day is!
大王，山田詹姆斯隆志 不知道什麼是114日
-What? -What do you do on 114?
-什麼？ -114日要做什麼？
You don't know it, James?
詹姆斯，你不知道嗎？
Well, you see, 114 is an event at our school.
114日是本校的一個活動
On this day, you can confess your love to the person you like.
在這一天，你可以對喜歡的人告白
"I love you! Will you be my girlfriend?"
“我喜歡妳 妳願意當我的女朋友嗎？”
And a good day for confessing your love like that is November 4.
11月4日是個適合告白的好日子
"114" sounds like, "Yes, I will," which is the answer you want.
114聽起來像是“好的，我願意”
That's right.
沒錯
However!
但是…
Each year, it's limited to…
每年限定告白的人數為…
-One person. -One person?
-一個人 -一個人？
Then even I can do it?
那我也可以告白嗎？
-I wouldn't do that if I were zoo!
-要是我是動物園，我就不會這樣做
-Our gags are in sync!
-心有靈犀
-This must be destiny!
-這一定是命運
End of show!
表演結束
But how come?
但有什麼不好呢？
It's fine if they say, "I like you too!"
只要對方說“我也喜歡你”就好啦
I love you!
我喜歡妳
If you're showered with flowers and everyone shouts "Nice couple,"
你會受到鮮花的洗禮 大家喊著“模範情侶”
it'll be your best memory of high school.
這會成為你高中生活最棒的回憶
But if you're rejected, a bucket of water is dumped on you…
但如果你被拒絕 一桶水就會潑到你身上
-Splash!
-嘩啦
Reminds me of last year.
讓我想到去年
Tezuka's utter destruction.
手塚慘不忍睹的情況
He went for that senior that looked like Meg Ryan.
他選那個長得像梅格萊恩的高三生吧
-I love you. -I'm sorry.
-我喜歡妳 -抱歉
After that, he became an insect freak.
在那之後，他就變成昆蟲控了
Morning.
早安
Yip yip!
嗷嗷
Are you guys dating?
你們是在交往嗎？
How disgusting! World's worst couple.
真噁心，世上最糟的情侶
Why don't you confess your love on 114?
你怎麼不在114日告白啊？
-Yuck! -Gross! You're grossing me out!
-好噁心 -噁心，好噁心
Gross!
噁心
That 114 stuff is bullshit.
114日根本毫無意義
Talk about lame crap.
真是無聊
Here.
拿去
What's this?
這是什麼？
The Nobuta Production Project notebook.
改造野豬計畫筆記本
What? Why do I have to have one that's just like yours?
我為什麼非得要有 跟你們有一樣的筆記本？
Matching with different colors.
顏色不一樣
They're all the same color.
顏色都一樣啊
What's this?
這是什麼？
"114 Love Project"?
“114日愛的大作戰”？
On 114, if Shuji confesses his love for Nobuta in front of everyone,
在114日 如果修二在大家面前跟野豬告白
you'll become popular in an instant.
野豬立刻就會大受歡迎
How come you guys never thought of such an easy thing before?
這麼簡單的事 你們怎麼會沒想到呢？
Are you insane?
你瘋了嗎？
Why do I have to do that?
我為什麼要那麼做？
What are you so mad about?
你在生什麼氣？
Not getting enough calcium?
缺乏鈣質嗎？
You don't get it, do you? Listen.
你搞不懂狀況，對吧？聽著
There's no point if you don't become popular by your own efforts. Okay?
如果不是靠自己的努力受歡迎 就沒有意義了，懂嗎？
That's what you say, but I bet you're just afraid you'll lose popularity.
話是這麼說啦 但你只是怕會失去人氣吧？
Are you actually a petty guy?
你其實是個小氣鬼？
Shuji's pathetic!
修二真可悲
No, that's not it!
才不是那樣
Yes, it is.
就是那樣
I have absolutely no intention of
我絕對不願意
losing popularity to make Nobuta popular.
犧牲自己的人氣，讓野豬受歡迎
Make Nobuta my girlfriend?
讓野豬當我的女朋友？
If I did that, my image that I've worked so hard to build would…
如果我這麼做 我辛苦建立的形象就會…
So, you see,
所以
doing that kind of thing ultimately wouldn't benefit Nobuta.
做這種事對野豬沒有好處
It wouldn't benefit her?
對野豬沒有好處啊？
That's right. We're doing this for her.
沒錯，我們要為了野豬著想
I am a hypocrite.
我是個偽君子
Me?
我？
-You don't want to? -No. That's not it.
-你不想嗎？ -不，不是那樣的
But, you know,
不過
making a confession of love in front of everyone… That's kind of…
在大家面前告白，感覺有點…
But everyone will celebrate us!
但是大家都會為我們慶祝啊
I heard rumors that all the couples from that day end up unhappy.
我聽說在那天交往的情侶 最後都很不幸福
I've never heard that.
我還是第一次聽到
Remember those seniors?
記得那對學長姐嗎？
They can't let anyone see them break up, so they're like a loveless couple.
因為不能在大家面前分手 他們就像沒有愛的老夫老妻
Then I'll confess my love.
那我來告白吧
I might get water dumped on me though.
雖然我可能會被潑水
I'd do that to you?
我會那樣對妳嗎？
No way! Never!
不可能，絕對不可能
But without this kind of opportunity, I can't tell how you really feel about me.
但若不趁著這個機會 我就無法知道你真正的心意了
Really?
真的嗎？
You won't even tell me your birthday.
你連自己的生日都不告訴我
Well, you see, if you knew my birthday, you'd try to do all kinds of stuff for me.
如果妳知道我的生日 就會為我做各式各樣的事
Okay? And my secret is…
懂嗎？而我的秘密就是…
you.
妳
Okay?
懂嗎？
What's that supposed to mean?
那是什麼意思？
Love sure is nice, isn't it?
不過，戀愛真好，對吧？
-It sure is. -Yes.
-是啊 -對
All that "love" crap is such BS. How stupid.
說什麼“愛”啊，蠢死了
Nobuta, your previous incarnation was a stone!
野豬，妳的前世是石頭
A stone?
石頭？
That's "D" rank.
也就是D級
Shuji.
修二
Shuji! Shuji Kiritani!
修二…桐谷修二
I'll tell you what your previous incarnation was,
我來告訴你，你前世是什麼
-so tell me your birthday. -What?
-告訴我你的生日 -什麼？
I never tell anyone my birthday.
我從不告訴別人我的生日
Why?
為什麼？
Because I hate having it celebrated when I don't want it.
因為我不想被迫慶祝生日
And I hate being forced to eat cake and stuff.
也討厭被迫吃蛋糕
There are people who hate that?
有人會討厭這些事嗎？
I mean, what do you do when you get a present you don't want?
要是收到不想要的禮物怎麼辦？
"Oh, I've always wanted this! Thank you so much!"
“我一直想要這個東西 太感謝你了”
Saying that is such a pain. It's exhausting and annoys me.
我討厭說這種話，又累又煩
-Tell me. I won't give you any presents. -No.
-告訴我，我不會送你禮物的 -不要
If you don't tell me, I'll give you a present every day.
如果不告訴我，我就每天送你禮物
No! I'm not telling you!
不要，我不要告訴你
-Tell me! -Oh, cut it out, would you?
-告訴我啦 -別鬧了，行嗎？
-What's wrong? Stressed out? -No.
-怎麼了？壓力大啊？ -才沒有
When is it?
那是什麼時候？
-Fine… November… -Yes?
-好吧…11月 -然後？
First.
1日
That's today.
就是今天
You're right! It is!
真的耶，是今天
That's why I didn't want to tell you.
所以我才不想告訴你們
Don't you dare say, "Let's celebrate."
千萬別說“去慶祝吧”
I've got it! Your previous incarnation…
我知道了，你的前世是…
A strong man!
大力士
A stone and a strong man.
石頭和大力士
I knew it.
我就知道
The best couple ever!
天生一對
-Excuse me. -No problem.
-不好意思 -沒事
Oh, you're early today, Mr. Saotome.
你今天真早到，早乙女老師
Greetings.
你好
-You know what? -What?
-妳知道嗎？ -是？
There was a beautiful lady in a kimono at the entrance just now!
剛才門口有一位穿著和服的美女
-You think it's the principal's daughter? -No.
-你覺得是校長的女兒？ -不是
I wonder who it is.
會是誰呢？
What?
怎麼了？
I smell the scent of sweet olive.
我聞到了桂花香
The woman in that kimono is meeting me for a marriage interview.
那個穿和服的女人是我的相親對象
No way!
-不會吧
You're doing a marriage interview?
你去相親？
That's so unfair!
太狡猾了
"Thus the man did embark the capital"
“此人踏上進首都的旅程”
"Did embark for the capital."
“踏上進入首都的旅程”
"Alas, he lamented departing his beloved.
他為了離開所愛而感傷
After remaining apart for three years,
離別三年後
his beloved had grown tired
他的愛人厭倦
of awaiting his return."
等待他的歸來”
Whoa! Look at that!
你們看
This sight will blow your mind!
這畫面太震撼了
-Get over here! Come on! -Cut that out!
快去看，快點
"I must say, I am very fond of you."
“我真的很喜歡妳
"I am devilishly fond of you!"
超級喜歡妳
"I have five million… five million yen in savings!"
我有五百萬元的存款”
"How delightful!"
“太棒了”
What? Wait!
什麼？等等
-Something's wrong! -What? Really?
-出事了 -什麼？真的假的？
The woman got angry and ran off!
那個女人氣呼呼地跑走了
Hallelujah!
哈利路亞
-No way!
-不會吧
Oh, no! What'll he do?
不好了，他要怎麼辦？
Tani! Investigate, please.
阿谷，請好好調查
You dropped your notebook.
妳的筆記本掉了
NOVEMBER 1: SHUJI KIRITANI'S BIRTHDAY
（11月1日，桐谷修二的生日）
Thank you.
不好意思
Didn't you say you don't tell anyone your birthday?
你不是說 不會告訴任何人你的生日嗎？
Yes, I said that.
對，我是說過
Your birthday was written in Kotani's notebook!
小谷的筆記本上寫著你的生日
Oh, that.
那個啊
What? You saw that?
什麼？妳看了那個筆記本啊？
Just by accident.
我不小心看到的
It fell on the floor
她的筆記本掉到地上
and it just happened to be open to that page.
剛好翻到那一頁
Oh, that's what it was?
原來如此啊？
That? You mean this. Right?
妳是指這個，對吧？
This was it.
就是這本
I must have dropped it, then Kotani found it and brought it to me.
我不小心掉了，小谷撿到後拿來還我
Oh, so this was your notebook.
原來這是你的筆記本啊
That's right.
沒錯
Sorry.
抱歉
So you write your own birthday in your own notebook?
你把自己的生日寫在筆記本上啊？
No. Actually, it was my brother who wrote it.
不，其實是我弟弟寫的
Come to think of it, it wasn't your handwriting.
說到這個，那確實不是你的筆跡
You could tell that just at a glance?
妳看一眼就看那麼仔細啊？
Yes.
對啊
That's scary.
-好可怕 -好尷尬
Sorry.
抱歉
Damn. I'm a good liar.
我還真會說謊
Hi.
你好
And apparently,
然後…
the lady asked him, "Who would be more important to you, me or your mother?"
那個女人就問他 “我跟你媽誰比較重要？”
What did Sebastian say?
賽巴斯汀怎麼說？
"My mother."
“我的媽媽”
His mother?
他的媽媽？
-Told you he was a mama's boy! -What a moron!
-我就說他是媽寶吧 -真是個白痴
Doesn't he know you lie in those situations?
他不知道在那種情況下要說謊嗎？
That's for sure!
就是說啊
Sebastian is such an idiot!
賽巴斯汀這個笨蛋
"Mother!"
“媽媽”
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Why are you apologizing?
你為什麼要道歉？
Good point.
說得也是
Is that really such a bad thing?
這樣真的那麼糟糕嗎？
Excuse me?
什麼？
Long ago,
以前
I was always getting in trouble, but my mom never gave up on me.
我總是惹麻煩，但我媽從沒放棄過我
Is it such a bad thing to love a mother like that?
這樣愛著母親有錯嗎？
No.
沒有
Is it such a stupid thing
無法對女人說謊
to not be able to lie to a woman?
真的有那麼蠢嗎？
No.
沒有
I will never think so.
我絕對不這麼認為
Good.
好的
I can smell sweet olive.
我聞到桂花的味道
No doubt about it, the aroma of heartbreak.
這絕對就是心碎的氣味啊
What will you use that for?
妳要用來做什麼？
Since it's his birthday, I still want to do something for him.
畢竟是他的生日 我還是想為他做點什麼
He said he doesn't like that.
他說他不喜歡
I don't think forcing it is a good idea.
我覺得這樣強迫人家不太好
That's why I'll make something that won't last.
所以我才要做一些不會存在太久的事
What the hell did you say?
妳說什麼？
You think I'm a fucking idiot?
妳當我是白痴嗎？
-You called me one first! -Shut your trap!
-是你先罵我的 -閉嘴
Ouch! Why do you do that?
好痛，為什麼要打我？
You always end up hitting me!
每次都打我
Can't you talk instead? You must be a moron.
有話不能好好說嗎？你肯定是白痴
What the fuck did you just say?
妳在說什麼？
Give me your name and address.
報上名字和地址
Who the fuck are you?
你他媽的是誰？
Stay out of this, Kusano.
別插手，草野
Every woman's heart is made out of glass.
每個女人的心都是玻璃做的
So don't you dare ever hit a woman.
所以不准對女人動手
You've got it all wrong! He's my boyfriend!
你誤會了，他是我男友
Is that so?
是嗎？
That's right!
沒錯
If she's the person you should be treating the best in the world,
如果她是你在這世上 最該好好對待的人
why are you hitting her?
為什麼還要打她？
Yip!
嗷
Who the fuck is this freak?
這個怪胎是誰？
What are you looking at?
看什麼看？
Butt out of my business, Kusano!
草野，少管閒事
"Butt out of my business, Kusano!"
“草野，少管閒事”
Bicycle.
腳踏車
Bye-bicycle!
-腳踏車溜囉
-Ciao!
-再見
Thank goodness. I made it in time.
太好了，我趕上了
There's something that I want to show you.
-我有東西想給你看 -好
Yip yip!
嗷嗷
-Can I? -Sure.
-可以嗎？ -可以啊
Here goes.
開始囉
HAPPY BIRTHDAY
（生日快樂）
-Happy birthday! -Thank you.
-生日快樂 -謝謝
Sorry. I threw it together with just what we had.
抱歉，我用手邊現有材料做的
It still looks great.
看起來還是很棒
-It does? -Yes.
-真的？ -真的
-Then let's eat. -Hold on!
-那就開動吧 -等一下
It would be a waste to eat it now. Can I take it home like this?
現在吃掉太可惜了 我可以帶回家嗎？
-Sure. -Can I?
-好啊 -可以嗎？
I'm so happy! Seriously!
我超開心的，真的
I'm the happiest guy in the world.
我是全世界最快樂的男人
Where did this cake come from?
這蛋糕哪來的？
That?
那個啊？
Mariko gave it to me.
是真理子給我的
Aren't you having any?
你不吃嗎？
Actually, I can't stand cake.
其實我很討厭蛋糕
In fact, whipped cream is the worst.
我最討厭鮮奶油了
Ouch.
好痛
You have to eat this.
你必須要吃
-What? -She put her heart into it.
-什麼？ -這是她用真心做的
Don't worry.
別擔心
I already showed her that I was really happy.
我已經表現出很開心的樣子了
But you have to eat it.
但還是要吃
That's the kind of stubborn thinking you need to change.
妳要改變這種頑固的想法
This kind of lie is okay. She's happy.
說這種謊言無所謂，她很開心
And I don't have to eat what I don't like. Everybody's happy.
我也不用吃不喜歡的東西，皆大歡喜
But she put her heart into this.
但她付出了真心
All that stuff about hearts is just creepy.
所有跟真心扯上邊的事都好噁心
In fact, it's about time you learned to lie.
事實上，妳也該學會說謊了
That's probably one of the reasons you get bullied.
那可能是妳被霸凌的原因之一
What does heart even mean?
真心算什麼？
It's so lame.
太噁心了
What's her problem?
她有什麼問題啊？
Well…
對了…
Since it's your birthday, Nobuta insisted on doing something for you.
因為今天是你生日 野豬堅持要為你做點什麼
Didn't I tell you not to do that kind of stuff?
我不是說別做這種事嗎？
Didn't I?
不是嗎？
It's not much,
雖然不多
but this is from our heart to you.
但這是我們對你的真心
Yip!
嗷
HAPPY BIRTHDAY
（生日快樂）
Why'd you…
你們為什麼…
Tell me the truth!
告訴我真相
Tell me!
告訴我
Love and courage are my only friends
愛與勇氣是我唯一的朋友
I saw him!
我看到他了
What's wrong, Mr. Hirayama?
怎麼了，大叔？
I saw… the Truth Man!
我看到真相大叔了
Who's the "Truth Man"?
誰是“真相大叔”？
What? You don't know?
什麼？你不知道？
He says, "Tell me the truth!"
他會說“告訴我真相”
And runs after you!
然後追著你跑
If you don't tell him, he won't stop following you!
如果你不告訴他，他會一直跟著你
-All right! -Tell me the truth!
-我知道了 -告訴我真相
All right! I'll tell you the truth.
好，我會告訴你真相
I've wanted to hit it rich with a new product
我想推出新產品賺大錢
and build my own company office.
蓋一間自己的辦公室
I know that's arrogant!
我知道這樣很自以為是
And I also thought I'd like to own a toy poodle.
我也想養一隻玩具貴賓狗
I'm sorry!
對不起…
If you lie to Truth Man,
如果你對真相大叔說謊
they say something awful will happen!
就會發生很糟糕的事
Like what?
像是什麼？
Like this
像這樣
or that…
或是那樣
That's scary!
-好可怕
-No! -Ouch!
-不要啊 -好痛
-Wow! -Did you see this?
你有看到嗎？
Whoa! This is bad!
不得了
Hey! Shuji!
修二
What? What is it? What's going on?
什麼？怎麼了？怎麼回事？
-Come on! -What is it? What is it?
-快點 -怎麼了？什麼事？
What is it? What is it?
到底是怎麼了？
When was this made?
這是什麼時候做的？
SHUJI + NOBUKO
（修二和信子）
Morning yogurt is good for the tummy!
早上吃優格有益腸道
Looks like something came out.
有新台詞了啊
Man…
真是…
Not our class again?
又是我們班嗎？
-Good idea!
-好主意
Do you even think that's possible?
妳覺得有可能嗎？
-It's totally possible. -It sure is!
-當然可能啊 -沒錯
There it goes!
進去了
-Okay, let's go! -Let's go!
-好，走吧 -我們走
TWO DAYS UNTIL 114.
（114日倒數兩天）
ZERO SIGN-UPS.
（零人報名）
Somebody signed up for 114!
有人報名了114日
-Who? A sophomore? -Who?
-誰？二年級的嗎？ -誰？
Someone in our class!
我們班上的人
And it's a girl!
而且是女生
-A girl? -Really?
-女生？ -真的嗎？
Which girl is it?
是哪個女生？
Quiet down!
安靜
Quiet down, would you? Quiet down!
安靜點，好嗎？閉嘴
Let's listen to what Tani has to say.
先聽聽阿谷怎麼說
-Come on. -All right.
-說吧 -好
This year, Kotani is doing it.
今年是小谷要告白
-Kotani? -What?
-小谷？ -什麼？
Who are you confessing your love to?
妳要對誰告白啊？
Who?
誰？
Yes. Who are you doing it to?
對啊，妳要對誰告白？
You know what? It's Shuji!
聽說就是修二
Me?
我？
Shuji!
修二
Special edition!
號外
We got the scoop on 114!
114日獨家報導
A miracle will happen on November 4!
奇蹟會在114日那天發生
That day…
那天…
-Mariko! -What?
-真理子 -怎麼了？
Shuji!
修二
-Shuji!
-修二
What will you do?
你打算怎麼做？
Will you trade Mariko Uehara for Kotani?
你不要上原真理子，要選小谷？
-What? Of course not! -That figures!
-什麼？當然不是 -我想也是
Aren't you a little tempted?
你都沒有一點心動嗎？
-Even a little? -Not tempted at all!
-一點點也沒有？ -完全沒有
-Why would I be? -I'm sorry.
-怎麼可能會有？ -對不起
Can I ask some questions?
我能問幾個問題嗎？
TWO DAYS UNTIL 114
（114日倒數兩天）
Getting water dumped on you
在所有人面前
in front of everyone
被潑水
is really, really brutal.
是一件很殘忍的事
Being a popular guy
當個受歡迎的人
isn't easy.
並不容易
Bunta! Your cola!
文太，你的可樂
What?
什麼？
Will you be okay, Shuji?
你沒事吧，修二？
But you can't say yes to her.
但你不能因為同情她而答應
I mean, then you'll have to date forever.
這樣你們就得一直約會了
Kotani must be on cloud nine!
小谷一定超開心的
Cloud nine!
超開心
-Congratulations! -Good for you!
-恭喜 -太好了
"Tomorrow" is written as "bright day." But will it be?
明日到底會不會是 “光明的日子”呢？
You'll just have to wait until tomorrow to find out.
明天就知道了
Nobuta.
野豬
I'm sorry,
對不起
but probably
但我明天…
I'll dump the water on you.
可能要潑妳水了
Okay.
好
I don't mind.
我不介意
Sorry.
抱歉
I apologize too, for causing you trouble.
我也很抱歉，給你添麻煩了
Bye.
再見
Hold on.
等一下
Do you think it's okay for the producer
你覺得要改造野豬的人
who's supposed to make Nobuta popular to say that?
說出這種話是對的嗎？
Do you?
合適嗎？
What is it?
怎麼了？
How do I give myself strength?
我要怎麼給自己力量？
Nobuta power charge!
野豬能量，注入
Oink!
噗
That will fill you full of energy!
這會讓妳精神百倍
This is a trick by Bando and the others.
這是坂東那群人設的陷阱
Yes, I know that.
是啊，我知道
She'll be massively depressed if you dump water on her.
如果你朝她潑水，她會非常沮喪
It's not the same as Bando and them dumping water on her.
那跟被坂東她們潑水是不一樣的
After you do it, just saying, "I didn't want to do that," won't cut it.
潑完水說“我不想那麼做” 是無法解決問題的
It's not that easy for a heart that's been crushed to heal.
被擊碎的心不可能這麼容易痊癒
Understand?
明白嗎？
I heard about Kotani.
我聽說小谷的事了
Oh, that? That thing?
那個啊？那件事啊？
Actually, I'm not sure what to do.
其實我也不知道該怎麼辦
You're such a nice guy, I'm kind of worried.
你是個很溫柔的人，所以我有點擔心
What? How come? There's no way I'd choose Kotani.
什麼？為什麼？我不可能選小谷的
Don't you worry.
別擔心
-Let's go. -But are you sure?
-走吧 -你確定嗎？
It's not like he's my friend or anything.
反正他本來就不是我朋友
Let's go.
走吧
Is that right?
是嗎？
Nobuta power charge!
野豬能量，注入
What do you want?
妳想怎樣？
Well…
那個…
I want to talk to you.
我想跟妳談談
Just with Bando.
我只想跟坂東談
Sure.
好啊
Please cancel the confession of love.
請妳取消告白的事
No point in telling me that.
妳跟我說也沒用
Once it's been submitted, it can't be canceled. That's the rule.
一旦報名了就無法取消，這是規定
I don't want to cause other people trouble.
我不想給別人添麻煩
Other people? You mean Shuji?
別人？妳是說修二嗎？
You really are an idiot.
妳真的是白痴
Shuji won't think twice about dumping water on you. It's obvious.
修二會毫不猶豫潑妳水 那還用說嗎？
No one would be fine with dumping water on someone.
沒有人可以毫不猶豫地潑別人水
But I don't mind at all. Especially if it's on you.
我完全可以，尤其是對妳這種人
I don't fit in at school.
雖然我在學校裡格格不入
But you stick out even more than I do.
但妳比我還要更不合群
You don't have to tell me that.
不用妳說我也知道
I've known it since preschool.
我從幼稚園就知道了
Don't you want to change?
妳不想改變嗎？
It's a little late to be a good girl.
現在當好女孩有點晚了
There's no way I can change.
我不可能會改變的
Anyone can change.
每個人都可以改變
What?
什麼？
I don't want to change anyway.
反正我也不想改變
You hit me.
我被妳打
And you're hit by your boyfriend.
而妳被妳男友打
How come you stupidly repeat the same thing over and over?
為什麼妳要這麼笨 讓同樣的事一再發生呢？
Why don't you want to try to change yourself?
妳為什麼不肯改變自己？
Anyone can change!
每個人都可以改變
Catherine! Catherine!
凱瑟琳…
Time is passing
時間不等人
What will you do, Kiritani?
桐谷，你要怎麼做呢？
About what?
妳在說什麼？
If it was just about brains,
如果只是腦袋的問題
you could figure out a way to get through this.
你就能想辦法度過這個難關
But when it comes to the heart…
但如果是心的問題…
You are
你已經…
Not who you used to be
不再是從前的你
Bang!
砰！
Everyone, let's do this! Let's do this!
各位，開動吧，來吧
Let's do this!
來吃吧
-Thank you for this food. -Go ahead.
-開動了
What? Me?
什麼？我？
Why do I have to do it?
為什麼是我？
Why can't Dad do it sometimes?
為什麼爸爸不能偶爾去開門？
-Thanks. -Sure.
-我開動了 -好
Let's see here…
來看看…
They're a friend of yours, Shuji.
是哥的朋友
Excuse me.
不好意思
What are you doing here?
你在這裡做什麼？
Are you a friend?
你是他的朋友？
Yes.
對，但現在我不是很確定
You save and wash disposable chopsticks?
你們會重複使用免洗筷啊？
That's so green!
真環保
What did you come here for?
你來幹什麼？
I came to threaten you.
我是來威脅你的
-What?
-什麼？
What's that?
那是什麼？
-Tiles? -Tiles.
-瓦片？ -瓦片
I've thought it over very carefully.
我仔細想過了
I won't stand for Nobuta getting water dumped on her.
我不能讓野豬被潑水
So…
所以…
if you dump water on her tomorrow, you'll pay.
如果你明天朝她潑水 你就要付出代價
Bang!
砰！
I'll pay?
我要付出代價？
That will be you tomorrow.
明天就換你了
Thank you.
謝謝
Okay.
好了
Wow! You're having miso oden tonight!
你們今晚吃味噌關東煮啊
Delicious!
好吃
Thanks for letting me drop by.
打擾了
What was that?
什麼情況？
No matter how much I think about it, I can't figure out what to do.
不管我怎麼想，都想不出辦法
I know!
我知道了
I'll decide by Ghost Leg.
用畫鬼腳來決定吧
FLOWERS, WATER, FLOWERS, WATER
（花、水、花、水）
Okay.
好了
Hello everybody!
大家好
The day has arrived!
這一天終於到了
This year's day for love has arrived!
今年的愛之日終於來臨了
Amazingly, this year's contestant is
想不到今年的挑戰者竟然是…
a woman!
一個女生
What a surprise!
出乎意料啊
-Okay, let's bring in the contestant. -Let's bring her in!
-好，我們請挑戰者出場 -請她進來吧
From Class B, second year, Nobuko Kotani!
2年B班的小谷信子
-Kotani!
-小谷…
Come on in!
請進
Up here please. This way.
請到台上來
Nobuko,
信子同學
the one you want to confess your love to is Shuji Kiritani from your class, right?
你想要告白的對象 是同班同學桐谷修二，對吧？
Now, it's time for Shuji Kiritani's entrance!
現在輪到桐谷修二登場了
Come in, please!
請進
-Shuji!
-修二…
-There he is, Shuji Kiritani!
-修二 -他來了，桐谷修二
What will his answer be?
他會做出什麼回應呢？
The crowd's really on fire!
全場氣氛沸騰
Okay. Now the stars of 114 are here.
好，114日的主角都到了
Will a new love be born
是會誕生一段新戀情？
or will it crumble to pieces?
還是兩人再也不相往來？
Kotani, make your confession of love, please!
小谷，妳可以告白了
Anything is fine. Let us hear it.
說什麼都好，讓我們聽聽看吧
People
每個人
can change, right?
都可以改變的，對吧？
What was that just now?
這什麼意思？
Was that some kind of code?
是某種暗號嗎？
Okay, Kiritani.
好了，桐谷
There are two ropes here.
這裡有兩條繩子
Grab onto both of them.
請你抓住兩條繩子
Right.
對
Of these two ropes,
在這兩條繩索中
one leads to flowers.
一條連接著花瓣桶
Flutters. "I love you!"
飛呀飛，我愛你
One leads to water.
另一條則是連著水桶
Splash! "Achoo!"
嘩啦，哈啾
What will become of Kotani's love?
小谷的戀情究竟會如何發展呢？
Now, Kiritani, give us your decision!
桐谷，請選擇
WILL IT BE FLOWERS OR WATER?
（會是花還是水？）
-Excuse me. -Yes?
-不好意思 -怎麼了？
Can I make a change?
我能做個改變嗎？
What?
什麼？
Change what?
改變什麼？
Can I change the person?
我可以換告白的人嗎？
You mean, you don't want Kiritani?
妳不要跟桐谷告白了嗎？
Shuji, you're out!
修二，換人
Out.
換人
Sorry for the trouble.
抱歉，給你添麻煩了
Bicycle.
腳踏車
-Bye-bicycle.
-腳踏車溜囉
-This is probably a good thing. -Yes. You're safe now.
-這也許是好事 -對，你現在安全了
Then, Kotani,
那麼，小谷
who will you confess your love to now?
妳現在要跟誰告白？
The person I actually love is
我真正喜歡的人是…
Kozue Bando.
坂東梢
Bando?
-坂東？
But she's a girl.
可是她是女生
Kozue Bando,
坂東梢同學
please.
拜託妳了
I'm not sure what to do now.
我現在也不知道該怎麼辦
In this day and age, anything goes, right?
現在這個時代 我們什麼都能接受，對吧？
You may be right.
也對
Then please come up, Bando!
坂東，請上台
-Bando!
-坂東…
Bando will dump water on her for sure.
坂東一定會朝她潑水
-What's Kotani thinking? -Yes.
-小谷在想什麼？ -對啊
This way, please. Sorry for suddenly calling you up.
這邊請，抱歉，突然叫妳上台
Sorry about this.
不好意思
Bando, I explained the rules a moment ago.
坂東，我剛才說明過規則了
Please give us your decision!
請妳做出選擇吧
What?
什麼？
What a miracle…
這是奇蹟
-What? -You pulled the wrong one!
-什麼？ -妳拉錯了
Why the flowers?
為什麼妳選花？
It was an accident.
我搞錯了
No way. That blows!
不會吧，糟透了
Well, this is really something!
真是太棒了
It's a miracle!
是個奇蹟
Shuji!
修二
Which one were you going to pull?
你本來要拉哪條繩子？
Does it really matter?
那重要嗎？
I bet you knew this would happen from the start, right?
你從一開始就知道會發生這種事吧？
But you know,
不過
I never thought Nobuta would say that.
我沒想到野豬會說那些話
And why did Bando drop the flowers?
為什麼坂東會選擇灑花呢？
Maybe she wanted to do the opposite of what everyone expected.
或許她想試著做 跟大家預期相反的事吧
You think so?
是嗎？
Maybe she wanted to believe that even she could change.
也許她想要相信，即使是她也能改變
Everyone, get out your notebooks.
兩位，請把筆記本拿出來
Oink oink.
噗噗
I would like the Nobuta Project team to go and view the autumn colors.
我希望改造野豬團隊 可以一起去欣賞秋色
-Not going. -How about it?
-我不要 -怎麼樣？
-I'm not going. -Fall colors.
-我說不要了 -紅色的楓葉
-I'm not going! -Yes!
-我不要去 -走吧
No! Stop it!
不，住手
-Tell me the truth! -Help!
-告訴我真相 -救命
Tell me the truth!
告訴我真相
-No! -Tell me the truth!
-不 -告訴我真相
No! Stop!
不，快住手
What was that?
那是怎麼回事？
-Truth Man. -What's that?
-真相大叔 -那是誰？
He's for real.
真的有這個人啊
What is that?
你在說什麼啊？
Wow!
了不起
This is Nobuta's.
這是野豬的筆記本
NAME: NOBUKO KOTANI
（姓名：小谷信子）
Awesome! Totally awesome!
太棒了…
Nobuta's a genius.
野豬是天才
Tell me the truth.
告訴我真相
No! It's him!
他來了
-Tell me the truth! -It's him!
-告訴我真相 -是他
Tell me the truth! Okay?
告訴我真相，好嗎？
Tell me the truth! Please!
告訴我真相，拜託
-The truth? -Yes.
-真相？ -對
Okay.
好
I like Nobuta.
我喜歡野豬
You mean, you're in love?
你戀愛了？
Yes. I'm in love.
對，我戀愛了
What?
什麼？
Love?
愛？
Really?
真的嗎？
I'm in love with Nobuta?
我愛上野豬了？
Really? I am?
真的嗎？是嗎？
Is that really the truth?
真的是這樣嗎？
The springtime of life! But it's fall.
我的春天來了？但現在是秋天耶
What? Seriously?
什麼？是真的嗎？
NAME: SHUJI KIRITANI
（姓名：桐谷修二）
FLOWERS, WATER
（花、水、花、水）
WATER
（水）
I was going to drop flowers on Nobuta.
我決定要灑花在野豬身上
Even if I had to sacrifice my popularity,
就算要犧牲我的人氣
I was going to drop flowers.
我也打算灑花
It's probably because I love those guys.
大概是因為我愛這兩個傢伙吧
I like the person I am when I am with those two.
我喜歡跟那兩人在一起時的我
NAME: AKIRA KUSANO
（姓名：草野彰）
This is his.
這是那傢伙的筆記本
WINNER
（贏家）
What's this?
這是什麼？
Even I couldn't believe it was true,
雖然就連我也不相信這種事
but it was, so I had to accept it.
但事實就是如此，我只好接受
A date! A double date!
約會，四人約會
-No! -High school is the time for love!
-不行 -高中生就該談戀愛
A cheerful and pure romance between a man and a woman!
一段開心又單純的戀愛
Let's do this!
就這麼做吧
-Love?
-愛？
Subtitle translation by: Brian Athey
字幕翻譯：黃雅婷